(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ある国にロバの娘がいました。
In a certain country, there lived a donkey girl.
周りから見た彼女は、それはそれは恵まれて見えました。
To those around her, she seemed very blessed indeed.
ですが、彼女の心は、決して豊かではありません。
However, her heart was by no means rich.
決められた人形のような生活。
A life like a preordained doll.
本当の私は、何だろう。
I wonder who the real me is.
大きな大きな犬がいました。
There was a very large dog.
周りを見渡すと、みんな小さく愛される犬ばかり。
Looking around, there were only small, beloved dogs.
自分だけ大きな姿に、大きな声。
Only they had a large body and a loud voice.
怖がらないで、一緒に遊ぼうよ。
Don't be afraid, let's play together.
とても格好つけたがりの猫がいました。
There was a cat who loved to put on airs.
みんなからは嘘つき呼ばわりされています。
They were called a liar by everyone.
本当はみんなを楽しますせたいだけなのに。
Even though they really just wanted to entertain everyone.
面白そうなことが大好きなだけさ。
I just love things that look interesting, that's all.
毎日仕事があってうらやましいでしょう。
You must be envious of having work every day.
楽しくて愉快な農場さ。
It's a fun and pleasant farm.
だけど毎日同じことの繰り返し。
But it's just the same thing day after day.
もっと私が輝ける場所があるんじゃないか。
Isn't there a place where I can shine more?
天下の大泥棒。
The world's greatest thief.
金銀財宝に目がありません。
They have a weakness for gold, silver, and treasures.
でも悪いことがしたいんじゃない。
But it's not like I want to do bad things.
貧しいみんなを笑顔にしたいだけなのに。
Even though I just want to make all the poor people smile.
自分も笑顔になれたらどれだけいいのかな。
How wonderful would it be if I could smile too?
大きな悩みを抱えたロバたち。
The donkeys carrying great worries.
君たちの物語が今、
Your story now,
ここから始まっていくのです。
Begins from here.
音楽。
Music.
それは私たちの人生に彩りを、勇気を、
It gives our lives color and courage,
そして夢を与えてくれる不思議な魔法。
and is a mysterious magic that gives us dreams.
これはそんな音楽の力を信じた動物たちの、
This is the story of animals who believed in such power of music...
冒険の物語
A story of adventure
Welcome to Bremen Music Festival!!!
おはようございます おはようございます
Good morning, good morning
おはよう おはようございます
Morning, good morning
おはようございます おはよう
Good morning, morning
私が歩けば聞こえてくる挨拶
Greetings that I hear when I walk
お腹が空けばならぶご馳走
Feasts lined up when I'm hungry
綺麗なドレスでお辞儀を済ませて
Bowing in a beautiful dress
判で押したような一日が始まる
A cookie-cutter day begins
お父様、おはようございます。
Father, good morning.
ん、おはよう。朝食は済ませたか？
Hmm, morning. Have you had breakfast?
はい！ところで最近街に出来た市場...
Yes! By the way, the market that opened recently in town...
朝食を済ませたなら早く着替えて。今日も忙しいぞ。
If you've had breakfast, change quickly. It's a busy day today.
お父様... わかりました。
Father... I understand.
決められた通り決められた笑顔で
With a set smile as determined
決められた人生を歩くの
Walking a predetermined life
何が私で何が私じゃないかさえ
Even what is me and what isn't
わからない
I don't know
手回しして歌を歌えば
If I crank the handle and sing a song
私は本当の私になる
I become the real me
虹色エリア 森のハリウッド
Rainbow-colored area, Hollywood in the forest
どこでもいける 何にでもなれる
I can go anywhere, I can be anything
歌の世界なら
In the world of song
石油の国の皆様、
To all people of the Oil Country,
この度ブレーメンミュージックフェスを開催いたします。
We are now holding the Bremen Music Festival.
様々な世界の様々な物語が集まる歌の祭典。
A song festival where stories from various worlds gather.
これより、あなただけのお気に入りの音楽を見つけてください。
From now on, please find your own favorite music.
私、決めたわ。
I've decided.
ブレーメンへ行こう 本当の自分を見つけよう
Let's go to Bremen, let's find our true selves
世界を変える私だけの
Changing the world, my own
歌を探して
Looking for my song
ところで、ブレーメンってどっちに行けばいいの？
By the way, which way should I go to Bremen?
こっち？
This way?
あっち？
That way?
ワン！ツー！
One! Two!
あ、また驚かせちゃった。
Ah, I surprised you again.
本当は遊びたかっただけ
Honestly, I just wanted to play
ちょっぴり声が大きくて
My voice is a little loud
ちょっぴり力が強くて
And I'm a little too strong
周りと違うだけで誰かを
Just being different makes me trouble
困らせてばかりのダメな奴さ
Everyone and makes me a failure
あなた、とっても素敵な声を持っているのね。
You have such a wonderful voice.
そうかな？声が大きすぎてみんなを驚かせちゃうんだ。
You think so? It's too loud and surprises everyone.
もう一度、聞かせてみて？
Let me hear it again?
ワン！
Woof!
それじゃあ、今度は音楽に合わせて。
Then, this time, to the music.
一回吠えて
Bark once
ワン！
Woof!
二回吠えて
Bark twice
ワン！ワン！
Woof! Woof!
ほら素敵でしょう
See, isn't it wonderful?
重なればオンナネいろだって
When combined, even same tones
居場所を見つけて
Find their place
響き始めるミュージック
And the music starts to resonate
ワン！ワン！ワン！ワン！ワン！ワン！
Woof! Woof! Woof! Woof! Woof! Woof!
ブレーメンへ行こう
Let's go to Bremen
この声使って生きること
Living by using this voice
きっとあるはずだから行こう
There must be a way, so let's go
一緒に
Together
さあ寄ってらっしゃい見てらっしゃい
Step right up, take a look
これより語るはいさましき勇者の
I shall now tell you a tale of a brave hero's
奇々怪々な冒険譚
Bizarre and mysterious adventure
旅立ちの朝　黒煙を
On the morning of departure, coughing out black smoke
吐きかける　おんぼろ馬車
Is a rickety old carriage
古の賢人に　玉座を
To the sages of old, let's hand over
空け渡そう
The throne
なんか凄そう！
Sounds pretty impressive!
ってどういう意味？
But what does that mean?
朝にムカついて　お年寄りに
He got annoyed in the morning and
席を譲ったってこと？
Gave up his seat to an elderly person?
さあいさましき勇者に
Now, for the brave hero...
賞賛をー
...praise be!
でも決まって　ほら吹き回り
But as always, the tall tales spread
現実超えた　空想こそが
Fantasy that transcends reality is...
美しいのに
...what's truly beautiful
つまりそれって
In other words,
共に奏でよう
Let's play together
まだ見ぬ空想のメロディを
A melody of fantasy yet unseen
遥か異国の地
In a far-off foreign land
開かれる宴
A feast is held
不可思議というのか　面白い
Call it mysterious or call it fun
新たな冒険か
A new adventure
よろしわが力を
Very well, I shall...
捧げよう
...offer my strength
ブレーメンへ行こう
Let's go to Bremen
空想がもっと輝ける
Where fantasy can shine even brighter
それが音楽だから行こう
Because that is music, let's go
一緒に
Together
一番美味しい役をやりましょう
Let's take on the best role
誰よりも悲しくて　あどけない役を
A role sadder and more innocent than anyone else
四角い海の果てでも　変わるがわる
Even at the edge of the square sea, ever-changing
人模様　演じていることそれさえも
Human drama, even the fact that we're performing
忘れる世界
Is forgotten in this world
みんな籠の中の問い
Everyone is a question inside a cage
いつか抜け出す日　夢見ん
Dreaming of the day we'll eventually break free
やっと手にしたその時　大空へと
And when we finally grasp it, toward the great sky...
戸惑う
...we hesitate
MYSTERIOUS
名前をあげて　安心させましょう
Let's give it a name and set it at ease
加護はかからない　あなたの
No protection will reach your...
MYSTERIOUS
星座を渡り紡ぎ　空へと逃げ仰せても
Even weaving through constellations to escape to the sky
体には熱たしさ　あどけないね　ねえ
The heat remains in your body, how innocent, right?
時計のない国で　誰もいらない
In a land without clocks, where no one is needed
この街で　淡い雪を降らす
In this town, making faint snow fall
青い太陽
Is the blue sun
窓もドアも風もなく　思い描く
With no windows, doors, or wind, imagining
不死の鳥　間違いも答えもない
An immortal bird, with no right or wrong answers
自由へと彷徨う
Wandering toward freedom
MYSTERIOUS
ひしめく果てを　弾ませ　守るのは
Making the crowded end bounce, what we protect is
横しまな清らかさ　抱きしめられては
A wicked purity, and once embraced...
飛び立つ
...it takes flight
旅路連れに
On this journey together
諦めの帳を吹き
Blowing away the veil of resignation
飛ばせ飛沫
Let the spray fly
濃い宵闇
In the deep twilight
手折られた翼
Plucked wings
跳ねて印した
Springing and marking
呪いは願い
Curses are wishes
祈りは出でずに
Prayers never coming out
ひとひらの仕草
A single petal's gesture
MYSTERIOUS
神や仏と悪魔の腕だち
Friends with gods, Buddhas, and devils
いてもいなくても
Whether they are there or not
私は MYSTERIOUS
I am MYSTERIOUS
貴方の
Your...
MYSTERIOUS
一番良い役を
The best role
やりましょう
Let's play it
ドラマツルギー
Dramaturgy
頭でわかっては嘆いた
I understood in my head and lamented
転がってく様子を笑った
I laughed at the way it rolls
寂しいとか愛とかわかんない
I don't know loneliness or love
人間の形は投げ出したんだ
I threw away my human form
抱えきれない言葉だらけの
Full of words I can't hold
存在証明を
An existential proof
この小さな箱から出らんない
I can't get out of this small box
気づいたら最後は逃げ出したい
I realized in the end I want to escape
僕ら全員演じていたんだ
We were all acting
エンドロールに向かってゆくんだ
Heading towards the end credits
さあ　みんな必死に
Come on, everyone desperately
役を演じて
playing your roles
傍観者なんていないのさ
There are no bystanders
“ワタシ”なんてないの　どこにだってないの
There is no “me”, nowhere
ずっと僕は　何者にもなれないで
I can never become anyone
僕ら今　さあさあ
We are now, come on
喰らいあって
devouring each other
延長戦サレンダーして
Surrendering the overtime
メーデー　淡い愛想
Mayday, faint civility
垂れ流せ　自己陶酔(アイゾウ)
Pour out self-narcissism (love and hate)
ドラマチックな展開をどっか期待してんだろう
Expecting a dramatic development somewhere
君も　Yes Yes
You too, Yes Yes
息を呑んで
holding your breath
采配はそこにあんだ
The command is there
ヘッドショット　騒ぐ想いも
Headshot, noisy thoughts too
その心打ち抜いてさ
Shoot through that heart
まだ見ぬ糸を引いて
pulling the unseen thread
黒幕のお出ましさ
The mastermind's entrance
空目に映るのは
What reflects in the trick of the eye is...
ふりだしに戻ってしまった
Back to square one
間違ってく様子を黙った
Kept quiet as things went wrong
僕ら全員無垢でありました
We were all innocent
いつのまにやら怪物になったんだ
Before I knew it, I became a monster
その全てを肯定しないと
Without affirming all of that
前に進めないかい
can't you move forward?
ああ　君にはきっと無理なんだ
Ah, it's surely impossible for you
だから君にはきっと無理なんだ
So it's surely impossible for you
いつの間にやら外野にいたんだ
Before I knew it, I was on the sidelines
そんなフレーズばかり飛ばしてきたんだ
I've been tossing only those kinds of phrases
みんな必死に自己を護って
Everyone is desperately protecting themselves
悔いの手を待ってるのさ
waiting for a hand of regret
答えたくないの　分かりたくないの
I don't want to answer, I don't want to understand
ずっと僕は　何者にもなれないで
I can never become anyone
だから今　前線
So now, from the front line
退りあって
withdrawing
その花びら喰らって
Devouring those petals
レッセフェール　淡い愛を
Laissez-faire, faint love
言葉なんて必要ないよ
No need for words
ドラマチックな展開はそっとじっとして暮れる
The dramatic development quietly fades away
君も　Yes Yes
You too, Yes Yes
息を呑んで
holding your breath
再会を誓いあって
Promising to meet again
ワンチャンスしかない僕と
With me who has only one chance
一瞬を賭けるのさ
Betting a single moment
クライマックスみたいだ
It's like the climax
手にあてがえるのさ
I can put it in my hand
ぽつりと鳴いた
I cried out softly
隠してた本当は
The truth I was hiding
どこにもない
is nowhere
笑ってきた奴等に
For those who laughed
居場所はない
there is no place
思い出して　ぽい捨てして感情はない
Remember, throw away, there's no emotion
流した涙　理由なんてない
No reason for the tears shed
優しさに温度も
Even in kindness
感じられない
no temperature can be felt
差し伸べた手に
In the outstretched hand
疑いしかない
there's only suspicion
抗って　愛を絶ってしまいそうになったんだ
Resisting, I almost cut off love
空ろな僕を覗き込んだんだ
I peered into my empty self
諦めかけていた
While you are around
人の回りあんたは
people who were giving up
いつも通り笑うように　お願いさ
Please, smile as you always do
君にはどんな風に見えてるんだい
How does it look to you?
呼吸を整えてさ
Calm your breathing
さあ　ずっと僕は　何者にもなれないで
Now, I can never become anyone
僕ら今　さあさあ
We are now, come on
喰らいあって
devouring each other
延長戦サレンダーして
Surrendering the overtime
メーデー　淡い愛想
Mayday, faint civility
垂れ流せ　自己陶酔(アイゾウ)
Pour out self-narcissism (love and hate)
ドラマチックな展開をどっか期待してんだろう
Expecting a dramatic development somewhere
君も　Yes Yes
You too, Yes Yes
息を呑んで
holding your breath
采配はそこにあんだ
The command is there
ヘッドショット　騒ぐ想いも
Headshot, noisy thoughts too
その心打ち抜いてさ
Shoot through that heart
まだ見ぬ糸を引いて
pulling the unseen thread
黒幕の...
The mastermind's...
あっちへふらふら、こっちへふらふらとさ
Wandering here and there, wandering there and here
その目に映るのは...
In those eyes reflected is...
ブレーメンを目指して旅立った、ロバ、犬、猫たち。
The donkey, dog, and cats that set out on a journey to Bremen.
自分の輝ける場所を求めて歩く足取りは、不安と期待の風が吹くけれど、
Though the wind of anxiety and expectation blows on their steps as they seek a place to shine,
同時に、今まで感じたことのない高揚感と自由。満ちていました。
At the same time, they were filled with a sense of excitement and freedom never felt before.
さあ、進もう。愉快な声が聞こえる方へ。
Now, let's move forward. Towards the direction of cheerful voices.
楽しい農場、
Happy farm,
楽しいだけの農場
Just a happy farm
愉快な農場、
Cheerful farm,
愉快なだけの農場
Just a cheerful farm
お日様ポカポカ、
The sun is warm and cozy,
楽しくて愉快なだけの農場
Just a happy and cheerful farm
とっても長閑で、いい歌ですね！
It's a very peaceful and nice song!
これはこれは、勿体無いお言葉。でも、
Why, those are generous words. But...
本当にそう思いますか？
Do you really think so?
ココ、ココ、こんなもんじゃない！
This, this, it's not like this!
ほとばしる俺のミュージック！
My music is gushing out!
ココ、ココ、こんな田舎で、
In this, this, in this countryside,
くすぶってる場合じゃねぇぜ！
There's no time to be smoldering!
もっと自分を試したい！
I want to test myself more!
もっと自由な音楽で！
With more free music!
オーバー、ドライブかけたら止まらないぜ！
Once I put it into overdrive, I won't stop!
ロックンロール！
Rock and roll!
あの、本当はこういう曲が好きなんです。ベイビー！
Um, actually, I like this kind of music. Baby!
一緒においでよ、ブレーメンでフェスがあってさ！
Come along with me, there's a festival in Bremen!
よかったら共に参らぬか？
If you'd like, shall we go together?
一緒に行ってるぜ！
We're going together!
このサウンドが宝の山さ！
This sound is a mountain of treasure!
オイエス、正面突破でかっ飛ばしてやるぜ！
Oh yes, I'm gonna blast through with a frontal assault!
ブレーメン、イェー！
Bremen, yeah!
サンキュー！
Thank you!
ブレーメンへ行こう、なりたい自分に正直に
Let's go to Bremen, be honest with the self you want to be
なれる世界を目指し行こう、
Let's head for a world where you can become that,
一緒に！
Together!
ねぇみんな、このお店に入らない？
Hey everyone, shall we go into this shop?
一息ついたら作戦会議をしましょう。
Let's have a strategy meeting after we take a breather.
ここはなんだか吠えるのに丁度いい場所だ。
This seems like a good place to howl.
アオー！
Awoo!
ついにメインディッシュか。
Finally, the main dish.
漆黒の闇夜に光る天使の微笑みを掴むための
I want to play the recipient for catching
レシピエントを奏でたい。
the angel's smile shining in the pitch-black night.
ドキドキ！ロックンロール！
Thump-thump! Rock and roll!
ハイ、ベイビーベイビー！
Hi, baby baby!
ふっ、なかなか面白そうな連中じゃないか。
Heh, they look like quite an interesting bunch.
えっ、あなた誰？
Wait, who are you?
変態？変態って初めて見た。
A pervert? I've never seen a pervert before.
変態じゃない！私こそは、
I'm not a pervert! I am the one
強きを挫き、弱きを助ける、正義の大泥棒だ！
who crushes the strong and helps the weak, the great thief of justice!
暗闇紛れ、頂戴する、
Slipping through the darkness, I'll take them all:
秘宝財宝、お宝全て
the secret treasures, riches, and gems.
狙い付けるわ、金持ち共。
I'll target the wealthy.
それだけが私の勇気！
That alone is my courage!
わかったらありがたみをマルっと置いてさっさと立ち去りな！
If you understand, leave your gratitude behind and get out of here quickly!
そんなこと言われても、俺たち、お金なんてナッシング！
Even if you say that, we have no money at all!
えっ、そうなの？
Eh, is that so?
あいや、騙されないぞ！
Ah, no, I won't be fooled!
貧乏人がそんなに楽しそうに笑えるはずがない！
There's no way poor people could laugh so happily!
貧しかった幼い頃、お腹を空かせた私は絶望の底にいた。
When I was poor as a child, starving, I was at the bottom of despair.
え、なんか始まっちゃった。
Oh, something started.
だからこそ私は、そんな人たちを笑顔にしたかった。
That's why I wanted to make those people smile.
それなのに…あぁ、それだけなのに…！
And yet... oh, even though it was just that...!
何故こんなに胸が痛む！
Why does my heart ache so much!
何故私はこんな方法しか知らないんだ…！
Why do I only know this way...!
人を笑顔にする方法？
A way to make people smile?
ふっ、愚問だな。
Heh, a foolish question.
僕にもわかってきたかも。
I think I've come to understand too.
でも、一人じゃできないだろ？
But, you can't do it alone, right?
だから、僕たちと！
That's why, with us!
ブレーメンへ行こう、僕らだけじゃない、
Let's go to Bremen, not just for us,
笑顔のため
but for the smiles
歌を歌おう、きっとできるはずさ。
Let's sing a song, I'm sure we can do it.
さあ行こう、ブレーメン！
Now let's go, Bremen!
ブレーメンへ行こう
Let's go to Bremen
Welcome to Bremen Music Festival!!
#アキロゼ生誕祭2024
#AkiRoseBirthday2024
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
秒針を噛む
Bite the Second Hand
生活の偽造 いつも通り 通り過ぎて
Faking my life, passing through as usual
1回言ったわかった戻らない
I said it once, I understand, there's no going back
確信犯でしょ？
You're doing it on purpose, aren't you?
夕食中に泣いた後 君は笑ってた
After crying during dinner, you were laughing
「私もそうだよ」って 偽りの気持ちが 誕生して
Saying "I'm the same too," a false feeling is born
吐いて 黙って ずっと黙って
Spit it out, shut up, shut up forever
何が何でも 面と向かって さようなら
No matter what, face-to-face, goodbye
する資格もないまま 僕は
Without even the right to do so, I...
灰に潜り 秒針を噛み
Diving into the ashes, biting the second hand
白昼夢の中で ガンガン砕いた
Smashed it hard within a daydream
でも壊れない 止まってくれない
But it won't break, it won't stop
本当を知らないまま 進むのさ
I'll keep going without knowing the truth
このまま 奪って 隠して 忘れたい
Just like this, I want to snatch it away, hide it, and forget
分かり合うまるひとつもなくても
Even if there's not a single bit of mutual understanding
会って 「ごめん」って 言えたら 良かった
It would have been better if we could meet and say "I'm sorry"
形のない言葉はいらないから
I don't need words without form
消えない後遺症
A lingering aftereffect
何でも受け入れていると
If you accept everything
言ったっきり もう 変えることはない
Once you've said it, you won't change it
でたらめでも 僕のためじゃなくても
Even if it's nonsense, even if it's not for me
君に守られた
I was protected by you
目も 口も 意味がないほどに
Eyes and mouth, to the point of being meaningless
塞ぎ込んで 動けない 僕を
Trapped and unable to move, me...
見つけないで ほっといてくれないか
Don't find me, just leave me alone?
どこ見ても どこにいても 明かない
Wherever I look, wherever I am, it won't open
灰に潜り 秒針を噛み
Diving into the ashes, biting the second hand
白昼夢の中で ガンガン砕いた
Smashed it hard within a daydream
でも壊れない 止まってくれない
But it won't break, it won't stop
演じ続けるのなら
If you're going to keep acting
このまま 奪って 隠して 忘れたい
Just like this, I want to snatch it away, hide it, and forget
分かり合うまるひとつもなくても
Even if there's not a single bit of mutual understanding
会って 「ごめん」って 言えたら 良かった
It would have been better if we could meet and say "I'm sorry"
形のない言葉はいらないから
I don't need words without form
すべて叫んで 痣はない
Scream everything out, there are no bruises
笑って転んで 情けない
Laughing and falling, it's pathetic
誰のせいでもないことを 誰かのせいにしたくて
Wanting to blame someone for something that's no one's fault
僕はいるのかな
Am I even here?
本当は分かってるんだ
Actually, I know
見放されても 信じてしまうよ
Even if I'm abandoned, I'll still believe
このまま 奪って 隠して 忘れたい
Just like this, I want to snatch it away, hide it, and forget
このまま 奪って 話したい
Just like this, I want to take it away and talk
分かり合うまるひとつもなくても
Even if there's not a single bit of mutual understanding
会って 「ごめん」って 言えたら 良かった
It would have been better if we could meet and say "I'm sorry"
疑うだけの 僕をどうして
Why do you... me, who only doubts
救い切れない 嘘はいらないから
I don't need lies that can't fully save me
今宵も頭上では
Tonight as well, above my head
綺麗な満月が キラキラ
A beautiful full moon is sparkling
幸せそうに 世界を
Happily... the world
照らしている
...shining down.
どうせ私は 出来損ないで
After all, I'm just a failure,
どうしようもなくて
and there's nothing I can do.
夜明け夢見ては
I dream of the dawn
地べた這いずり回る
while crawling on the ground.
それでも誰かに 見つけて欲しくて
But still, I want someone to find me,
夜空見上げて叫んでいる
so I'm looking up and shouting at the night sky.
逃げ出したいや 逃げ出せない
I want to run away, but I can't;
明るい未来は見えない
I can't see a bright future.
ねえ それでもあなたに
Hey, I still want you
見つけて欲しくて 蝶のように舞い上がるの
to find me, so I'll soar like a butterfly.
欠けた翼で飛ぶよ
I'll fly with these broken wings,
醜い星の子 ミカヅキ
the crescent moon, child of an ugly star.
今宵も月は 綺麗な満月じゃないけど
The moon tonight isn't a beautiful full moon,
誰かの腕に 抱かれて眠っている
but it's sleeping, held in someone's arms.
どうせ私は 一人の夜に
After all, I'm crushed by the lonely nights,
押し潰されては
shattered by the solitude,
誰にも見えない 夜闇這いずり回る
crawling through the darkness, invisible to all.
それでも誰にも 負けたくなくて
But still, I don't want to lose to anyone,
夢中で爪も掻いている
so I'm desperately clawing my way through.
追いつきたいや 追い越したいや 夢に見たような世界
I want to catch up, I want to overtake, into the world I've seen in my dreams.
ねえ それでも誰かと 比べてばっかり
Hey, I'm still just constantly comparing myself,
周りを見ては立ち止まって
stopping as I look at those around me.
欠けたものを探した
I searched for what was missing;
そんな自分を変えたい
I want to change that part of myself.
それでもあなたと 同じ景色が また見たいから
But still, I want to see that same view with you again.
泣き出したくても 投げ出したくても
Even if I want to cry, even if I want to give up,
諦めたりはできない
I can't bring myself to quit.
それでもあなたに 見つかるように
But still, so that you'll find me,
蛹は強く手を伸ばすの
this chrysalis is reaching out its hands.
欠けたもの抱きしめて
Embracing what's broken,
願いを放つよ ミカヅキ
I'll release my wish, the crescent moon.
それでも誰かに 見つけて欲しくて
But still, I want someone to find me,
夜空見上げて叫んでいる
so I'm looking up and shouting at the night sky.
泣き出したいけど 泣き出さない
I want to cry, but I won't cry;
もう後戻りなどできない
there's no turning back now.
ねえ それでもあなたに 見つけて欲しくて
Hey, I still want you to find me,
蝶のように舞い上がるの
so I'll soar like a butterfly.
欠けた翼で飛ぶよ
I'll fly with these broken wings,
醜い星の子 ミカヅキ
the crescent moon, child of an ugly star.
光を放つよ ミカヅキ
I'll release my light, the crescent moon.
今宵も月は 綺麗な満月がキラキラ
The moon tonight is a beautiful full moon, sparkling bright.
次は君の番だと
Telling me it's your turn next,
笑っている
as it smiles down.
Welcome to Bremen Music Festival!!
楽しかったパーティーも いよいよクライマックス
This fun party is finally reaching its climax.
次は 飛び入り参加の 異色のユニットが登場です！
Next up, a unique unit of surprise guests will appear!
石油の国のプリンセス ロバ
The Princess of the oil country: Donkey!
大地を揺らすミラクルボイス イヌ
The miracle voice that shakes the earth: Dog!
空想世界の探求者 ネコ
The explorer of the imaginary world: Cat!
オレの音楽を聴け！ ニワトリ
Listen to my music! Chicken!
心優しきイリュージョニスト ドロボウ
The kind-hearted illusionist: Thief!
音楽の力で奇跡を起こす！
Create miracles with the power of music!
ブレーメン・アニマルチーム！
Bremen Animal Team!
いくつかの出会いが 私に教えてくれた
Many encounters have taught me
自分で選ぶ日々が 私を私にさせる
The days I choose for myself make me who I am
この声だって 誰かきっと気づいてる
Someone must have noticed this voice too
だから恐れず 精一杯の僕でいよう
So, without fear, I'll be the best I can be
埋もれぬような空言だって
Even if it's an unburied empty promise
夢と呼べる場所がある
There's a place I can call a dream
自由な羽ばたきで 巻き起こす風も
Even the wind caused by the free flapping of wings
いつか誰かの憧れに 変えてみせるから
I'll show you that one day
I'll turn it into someone's admiration
歌おう Music for the world
Let's sing, Music for the world
響け 届け 世界へ
Resonate, reach out to the world
この魔法の力 信じて
Believe in this magical power
高らかに僕らの歌
Loudly, our song
やっと見つけた 笑顔の届け方
I've finally found how to deliver a smile
簡単な言葉ばかりじゃないけれど
It's not just simple words, but...
声を合わせれば きっとできる
If we join our voices, I'm sure we can do it
試してみて
Try it
この呪文を
this spell
さあ一緒に
Come on, together
歌おう Music for the world
Let's sing, Music for the world
響け 届け 世界へ
Resonate, reach out to the world
この魔法で変わるすべて
Everything changes with this magic
目に焼き付けて
Keep it in your mind's eye
歌おう Music for the world
Let's sing, Music for the world
誰も一人じゃないさ
No one is alone
この声でつなぐ心よ
Our hearts connected by this voice
大空を超えて
Beyond the vast sky
歌おう
Let's sing
僕らの意味を教えてくれる
They tell us the meaning of our existence
暖かな音の波 重なって
Warm waves of sound overlap
いつでも夢を 与えてくれる
Always giving us dreams
それが音楽 だから
Because that's what music is
ブレーメン
Bremen
ブレーメンへ行こう
Let's go to Bremen
アローナ！
Alona!
アキロゼ生誕祭2024をご覧の皆様、ありがとうございます！
Thank you to everyone watching
AkiRose Birthday Festival 2024!
おっと、まだ終わりじゃないから最後までチャンネルはそのまま！
Wait, it's not over yet,
so keep the channel right here until the end!
ということで、今年はなんと、ついに憧れのオースタープロジェクトさんに
So, this year, I finally had the long-awaited OSTER project
オリジナルミュージカルを作っていただきました！
create an original musical for me!
どう？どうだったかな？
How was it? What did you think?
みんなからの感想いっぱい聴けたら嬉しいので、
I'd love to hear lots of your thoughts, so
ハッシュタグ「#アキロゼ生誕祭2024」をつけていっぱいポストしてね！
please post a lot using the hashtag #AkiRoseBirthdayFestival2024!
エゴサで探しに行くからね。待ってるよ！
I'll be looking for them on social media. I'm waiting!
そして、チャンネル登録、今回出演メンバーも含めて、
And please subscribe to the channel, including the members who performed today,
ぜひ、まだの人はよろしくお願いします！
if you haven't already!
メンバーシップ登録してくれてる人もありがとう！
Thank you to those who have signed up for membership too!
実はこの後メンバー限定でアフターライブが…
Actually, after this, a members-only after-live...
と言いたいところだったんだけど、本編に全部注ぎ込んでしまいまして、
is what I wanted to say, but I poured everything into the main show,
ライブはないです。
so there won't be a live.
ただ、未公開のオフショットとかを公開予定なので、
However, I'm planning to release some unreleased off-shots,
ぜひメンバー登録して待っててくれると嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you could register as a member and wait for them.
そして、明日に...
And, tomorrow...
今回のミュージカルの制作秘話とか裏話とか、
I'll be talking about the production secrets and
その辺の感想をいっぱいギュッと詰めて
behind-the-scenes stories of this musical, along with
お話できたらいいなって思ってるので、
a lot of my thoughts, so I'm looking forward to it.
その配信もお楽しみに！
Please look forward to that stream!
ということで、皆さんお待たせ。
And so, everyone, sorry to keep you waiting.
グッズ告知タイムです！
It's time for the goods announcement!
生誕記念グッズ、頑張って作らせていただきました。
We worked really hard on these birthday
こちら、ドン！
commemorative goods. Here they are, boom!
アキロゼ 誕生日記念2024
Aki Rosenthal Birthday Commemoration 2024
アキ・ローゼンタール誕生日記念2024のグッズは、
The Aki Rosenthal Birthday Commemorative
今回のミュージカルのテーマにもなっている
2024 goods are designed with the theme of
ブレーメンの音楽隊をイメージして作らせていただきました。
this musical, "Town Musicians of Bremen," in mind.
まずは、
First up,
Fantasia of Bremen リバーシブルトートバッグ。
the Fantasia of Bremen Reversible Tote Bag.
イラストは夏灯先生に描いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Natsutou-sensei.
ブレーメンの音楽隊の世界から飛び出すアキロゼ & マスコットを描いていただいてます。
It features Aki Rosenthal and her mascots jumping out
今回は、普段使いもできるようにリバーシブルデザインをしているので、
of the world of the Town Musicians of Bremen. This time,
たくさん推し活でアピールしたい時も、おしゃれにこなれた感じで使いたい時も、
it has a reversible design so you can use it
ぜひぜひいっぱい使ってくれると嬉しいです。
every day, whether for fandom or stylishly. I'd be
超可愛い。
happy if you used it a lot. It's super cute.
続いて、
Next,
Fantasia of Bremen アクセサリースタンド。
the Fantasia of Bremen Accessory Stand.
ブレーメンといえばシルエットが特徴的だったりするので、
Since Bremen is known for its silhouettes,
シルエットのデザインのグッズを作ってみました。
I tried making a silhouette-themed item.
すごい可愛い感じに仕上がってます。
It turned out really cute.
ま、アクセサリーに限らず色んなものをかけたりとか、
You don't have to just use it for accessories;
デスク周りや玄関周りに置いても可愛いと思います。
it would look cute on your desk or entryway.
さらに、
Furthermore,
Fantasia of Bremen ピンバッジ。
the Fantasia of Bremen Pin Badge.
さっきのバッグとかアクセサリースタンドとかにつけても可愛いです。
It's also cute to pin it on the tote bag or stand.
そしてそして、
And also,
アキロゼぬいぐるみ マーチングver.が、ついに登場！
the Aki Rosenthal Plushie - Marching Version
こちら、アキロゼ5周年ライブの時に発表したオリジナル曲、
is finally here! This is the marching outfit
「キミにまつわる運命事情」のジャケットイラストになっているおしるこ先生デザインの
designed by Oshiruko-sensei for my original song
マーチング衣装がぬいぐるみになっちゃいました！
announced during my 5th-anniversary live.
ドンドンパフパフ！
It's now a plushie! Bada-bing, bada-boom!
これもね、トートバッグにつけたりしても可愛いし、
This would also be cute on the tote bag,
ぜひいっぱい楽しんで可愛がってください。
so please enjoy it and give it lots of love.
さらに、今回もボイス出ます！
And once again, there will be a voice pack!
「生誕祭のあとで 〜お耳はむはむ〜」というような、ちょっと気になるタイトルになってると思うんですが、
The title is "After the Birthday Party: Ear Nibbling," which might sound a bit intriguing,
今回もアキロゼ自分で書きました。
but I wrote the script for it myself this time too.
ということは、
Which means,
それすなわち、ちょっとドキドキが強めかもしれません。
that it might be a bit more heart-pounding than usual.
ASMRボイスをたっぷり楽しんでもらうために KU100君で収録させていただきました。
I recorded it using the KU100 to ensure you
ぜひお楽しみに！
can enjoy the ASMR. Please look forward to it!
今回のグッズ、フルセットご希望予定の方は、いらっしゃいますか？
Is anyone planning to get the full set of these goods?
いらっしゃいますよね！
I'm sure there are!
なんと特典があります。
Well, there's a special bonus for you.
夏灯先生描き下ろしのイラストポストカードがついてきます。
It comes with an original illustration postcard
しかも、数量限定バージョンのほうには、
by Natsutou-sensei. What's more, for the
アキロゼ書きます。
limited-edition version, I'll be writing on it.
直筆サインもついちゃうよ！
It'll include my handwritten signature!
数量限定を超えてしまうと箔押し複製サインになっちゃうので、
If the limited quantity runs out, it'll be a
早い者勝ちです！
foil-stamped replica. It's first come, first served!
このあと配信終了後22時から販売開始になるので、
Sales will start at 10:00 PM tonight after the
ぜひ今のうちにチェックチェック！
stream ends, so be sure to check it out soon!
改めて、アキロゼ生誕祭2024応援してくれてありがとうございました。
Once again, thank you so much for supporting Aki
エンドロールでは、今回出演してくれたみんなとたくさんお話をしたので、
Rosenthal's Birthday Festival 2024. In the end credits,
ぜひ最後までご注目ください。
I talked a lot with everyone, so please stay tuned.
メンバー限定の未公開オフショットもお楽しみに。
Look forward to the exclusive behind-the-scenes
メンバー登録も待ってるよ。
footage for members too. Join as a member!
制作秘話や裏話は明日改めてするので、そちらもお楽しみにね。
I'll be sharing production secrets tomorrow,
それではみんな今日はアキロゼ生誕祭2024、3DLIVE見に来てくれてありがとう。
so look forward to that. Thank you all for coming
これからもいっぱい応援してね。
to see the 3D Live today. Please keep supporting me!
それでは、今回出演してくれたゲストの紹介をしていきましょう！
Now, let's introduce the guests who appeared today!
まずは、大きなイヌ役をやってくれたころね。
First up is Korone, who played the role of the big dog.
はーい！
Hi!
楽しかった！
That was fun!
楽しかったね。
It sure was.
楽しかった。
It was fun.
うん。
Yeah.
ホロライブの...
Hololive's...
ホロライブのイヌ、ゲーマーズの戌神ころねでーす。よろしくお願いします。
Hololive's dog, Inugami Korone from Gamers.
はーい、もうこれは今回適役ぴったりの、ころねしかできないような役だったんだよ。
Yes, it was a perfect role that
そうだよね、イヌといえばだもんね。
only Korone could pull off. Right, because
でもイヌといえばっていうかイヌだもんね。
when you think of a dog... but you *are* a dog.
そうだ、イヌだからね。イヌそのものだからね。
That's right, I'm a dog. I'm a dog itself.
もうありのままを見せてくれたってことだ？
So you just showed us your true self?
そう、野生に戻ったよ、今日は。
Yes, I went back to the wild today.
あ、野生感戻ってたんだ。
Oh, so your wild instincts were back.
え、ちなみにミュージカルやってみてどうだった？
By the way, how was it doing a musical?
Inugami Korone
どうなるか、こんなもん、って感じだったんだけど
I was like, "How is this gonna go?"
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
あきちゃんがね、もう色々教えてくれたりとか
Aki-chan taught me many things...
一緒にね、あの、やってくれたりとかして
...and worked with me,
なんとか！
so somehow!
なんとかできた！
I managed to do it!
なんとかできた！いやー
You managed to do it! Wow.
超可愛かったし最高だったって。
You were super cute and it was the best.
嬉しいー。
I'm so happy.
本当楽しかったね。
It was really fun, wasn't it?
ね、ころねのお気に入りポイントとか、ここ見てポイントみたいなのってあったりするの？
Hey, did you have a favorite part or a "watch this" moment?
お気に入りは、でもやっぱりころねが一番最初にあきちゃんに出会うじゃん。
My favorite is, after all, the scene where I first meet Aki-chan.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
そこで、その、なんかころねが悩んでる時に、あきちゃんが「吠えてみて」ってシーンがあるんだけど
There, when I'm troubled, there's a scene where Aki-chan says, "Try barking."
うん。
Yeah.
そこのなんか、なんか友情の芽生えじゃないけど
It's like the beginning of a friendship...
そこのね、あきちゃんとの絡みがすごい好きだから、ね、またみんな見て欲しいですね。
I really like that interaction with Aki-chan, so I want everyone to see it again.
うわー、嬉しい！あそこのワンって吠えてくれるところね、大好きなんだよね。
Wow, I'm glad! I love that part where you go "Woof."
そう、「吠えてみて」「ワン！」って。
Yeah, "Try barking," "Woof!"
あそこね、もうてぇてぇだから。
That part is just so "teetei" (precious).
あ、てぇてぇだよね。
Ah, it is "teetei."
あ、てぇてぇなのかな？あ、てぇてぇではないか？
Wait, is it "teetei"? Maybe not "teetei"?
いや、めちゃくちゃ可愛くて、アキロゼも大好きポイントだよ、ここ。
No, it's incredibly cute, and it's a part I love too.
嬉しいー。
I'm so happy.
ね、めちゃ楽しかった。ありがとねー！
Yeah, it was so much fun. Thank you!
本当楽しかった！
It was really fun!
はい、じゃあ、それじゃあ、ころね、ありがとねー！
Alright then, Korone, thank you!
あきちゃん、誕生日本当におめでとう！
Aki-chan, happy birthday!
あー、ありがとー！バイバーイ！
Ah, thank you! Bye-bye!
まったねー！バイバイ！
See you! Bye-bye!
Nekomata Okayu
それでは続いて、中二病の猫役をやってくれた、おかゆ！
Next up, Okayu, who played the role of the chuunibyou cat!
はーい、もぐもぐおかゆー！どうも、猫又おかゆです。
Hi, Mogu Mogu Okayu! I'm Nekomata Okayu.
お疲れ様ですー！おかゆー！
Good job! Okayu!
あきちゃーん！
Aki-chan!
いや、一緒にね、おかゆんとミュージカルやりたかったんだよー！
I really wanted to do a musical with Okayun!
いや、僕もさ、毎年あきちゃんがミュージカルやってるの見てて
I've also been watching Aki-chan do musicals every year,
いつか僕も参加したいなと思ってたから
and I've always wanted to join one day,
今回こうやって声かけてもらえて、すっごい嬉しかったよ。
so I was really happy to be invited this time.
えー、好きー。
Aww, love you.
僕も好きー。
I love you too.
おかゆんはさ、今日やってみてどうだった？
Okayun, how did you feel doing it today?
いやー、もうなんか、僕は、よし、かっこいい猫の役だぞ、と思って
Well, I thought, "Alright, I'm playing a cool cat role,"
もういっぱい格好つけてやってたから
and I was doing it with a lot of style,
最後にあきちゃんが僕の名前呼ぶ時に、「中二病猫」みたいに言ってて
but then at the end, when Aki-chan called my name, she called me a "chuunibyou cat,"
「え？」ってなったんですけど、あきちゃん？
and I was like, "Wait, what?", Aki-chan?
おままま、まあちょっとね、途中の歌の歌詞とかをよく見てもらうと
Well, if you look closely at the lyrics of the songs in the middle,
結構なんか、中二感溢れる感じがね...
they're quite full of that chuunibyou vibe...
そうだったのー？
Is that so?
めっちゃかっこいい猫だと思ってやってたよ！
I was doing it thinking I was a super cool cat!
あえて中二病の猫だよとはおかゆに伝えてなかった。
I intentionally didn't tell Okayu that it was a chuunibyou cat role.
うん、今、今初めて知った、今！
Yeah, I just found out right now, just now!
いや、でもその格好つけがね、やっぱかっこいい感じになってたから、まあちょうど良かったんじゃないかな。
But that posing made you look really cool, so I think it worked out perfectly.
良かった、じゃあ、じゃあいいよ、じゃあいい！
Good. Then it's fine. It's fine!
え、なんか二人でさ、掛け合ってハモるところ、めっちゃ好きなんだよなー。
I really love the part where we harmonized together.
わかるー！
I know, right!
ねー、歌っててめっちゃ気持ち良かったよ。
Yeah, it felt so good singing it.
そこをみんなもちょっとな、いっぱい聴いて欲しいところだよね。
That's a part I really want everyone to listen to a lot.
ね、いっぱい聴いてほしい。
Yeah, I want them to listen a lot.
はい、じゃあ今日は一緒にやってくれてありがと、楽しかったよ！
Alright, thanks for performing with me today. It was fun!
こちらこそだよ！めっちゃ楽しかった！
Me too! It was a lot of fun!
あ、あきちゃん、今日はお誕生日おめでとうだよ！大好きだよー！
Oh, Aki-chan, happy birthday! I love you!
ありがとー！大好き！モグモグ、バイバーイ！
Thank you! I love you! Mogu mogu, bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
Takanashi Kiara
はーい、それでは続いて、鶏役をやってくれた、キアラ！
Alright, next up is Kiara, who played the role of the chicken!
キッーケリキー！イエーイ！
Kikkeriki! Yay!
ホロライブEnglishの小鳥遊キアラです。鶏役だったけど...
I'm Takanashi Kiara from Hololive English. I was the chicken, but...
これは、鶏だった、ということじゃないですからね。
it doesn't mean I actually was a chicken.
これでも、不死鳥です。不死鳥ですよ！
I'm still a phoenix. A phoenix, you know!
あ、不死鳥の方？
Oh, the phoenix?
不死鳥だよ！
I am a phoenix!
鶏じゃない？
Not a chicken?
鶏...ま、今日だけ鶏！
Chicken... well, just for today, a chicken!
今日だけ鶏ね。
Just for today.
はい。いやー、すごいたのしかったよキアラ、一緒にやってくれてありがとねー！
Yeah. Wow, it was so much fun Kiara. Thank you for doing this with me!
イエーイ！もちろん、もちろん！
Yay! Of course, of course!
ミュージカルやってみてどうだった？
How was it doing the musical?
うん、なんか繋がってる物語があるのがすごい良いと思ったし
Well, I thought it was really nice that there was a connected story,
なんか感動する演奏がとってもいいなと思ったのと
and I thought the moving performance was very good,
なんか頭の中で「ミュージカル」をイメージしてやってみたので、めっちゃ楽しかったよー！
and I tried to imagine a "musical" in my head while doing it, so it was a lot of fun!
イエー、もうキアラのパートはね、とってもね、この曲の中でも面白いパートだったと思うし
Yay! Kiara's part was a very interesting part in this song, I think,
うん、面白かった！
Yeah, it was funny!
キアラが濃いでしょう？
Kiara was so intense, right?
あ、そう、そうだね！「ベイベー、ベイベー、ベイベー、ベイベー」
Oh, yes, right! "Baby, baby, baby, baby!"
ギターも弾いてたし、もちろんギター弾けます！
I was playing the guitar too, and of course I can play the guitar!
嘘ー！
No way!
完璧！ありがと。嘘！
Perfect! Thanks. Just kidding!
嘘かい！
You're kidding?!
いや、でも本当に一緒にねやってくれて...
No, but seriously, for doing this with me...
Takanashi Kiara
呼べて嬉しかった。ありがとう。
I'm glad I could invite you. Thank you.
うん。ありがとう。
Yeah. Thank you.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
天才。アキ先輩は天才。
Genius. Aki-senpai is a genius.
いやー、そんな褒めても何も出ないよ。
Aw, even if you praise me that much, I won't give you anything.
ひひっ。
Hehe.
じゃあ、また。
Well then, see you.
またなんか一緒にやろうね。
Let's do something together again.
やろう！ありがとう呼んでくれて。
Let's! Thanks for inviting me.
お誕生日おめでとう。おめでとう。
Happy Birthday. Congratulations.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
チュチュチュ。バイバーイ！
Chu chu chu. Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
テンション高いな。
Her energy is high.
それでは続いて、泥棒役をやってくれたマリンちゃん。
And now, next is Marine-chan, who played the role of the thief.
Houshou Marine
はーい！
Heeey!
あほーい！宝鐘海賊団船長の宝鐘マリンです！
Ahoy! I'm the captain of the Houshou Pirates, Houshou Marine!
やったー！やりきった！
We did it! We saw it through!
マジではまり役だったと思うんだけど、今回やってみてどうだった？
I think you were a perfect fit for the role, but how did you feel doing it this time?
いや船長、なんか初めて気づいたんだけど、なんかこういうのすごい好きかも知れないわ。
Actually, I just realized this for the first time, but I might really like this kind of thing.
あ、本当に？
Oh, really?
え、なんかめちゃくちゃいい経験できた。本当にタルタルありがとう。
Yeah, it was such a great experience. Thank you so much, Tartar.
えっ、タルタルって呼ばれるの実は嬉しいんだよね。
Eh, actually, I'm happy to be called Tartar.
あ、ちゃんと呼びますよ、もちろん。
Ah, I'll definitely call you that, of course.
でもなんかやっぱり、ミュージカルっていう経験自体、もちろん当然なくて。
But you know, I obviously didn't have any experience with musicals before.
で、なんかこういうすごい、はまり役をね、もらえて、もうすっごい楽しくて。
And to get such a perfect role, it was just so much fun.
セリフを言うのがもうめちゃくちゃまず楽しくて。
First of all, saying the lines was extremely fun.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
歌を、なんかすごい船長が好きなタイプの、ちょっとね、何系っていうんだろう。ちょっとアハン系っていうの？
The song was the type I really like, a bit... how should I put it? A bit of an "Ahan" style?
アハン系よね。
An "Ahan" style, right.
そうそう。やらせてもらって。みんなでね、大団円迎えて。マジで感動しちゃったわ。本当に楽しかったです。
Yes, yes. I got to do it. And ending with everyone in a grand finale. I was truly moved. It was really fun.
よかった。
I'm glad.
実はね、今回ミュージカルをやろうと思って、いろいろ考えたの。最初からいろいろストーリー考えたりとかしてたんだけど。
Actually, when I decided to do a musical this time, I thought about a lot of things. I was thinking about the story and everything from the start.
いや、泥棒役はこれマリンちゃんしかいないなと思って。
And I thought, "There's no one else but Marine-chan for the thief role."
いやー、ありがとうございます。もう海賊なんだから、もう。
Aw, thank you so much. Well, I am a pirate, after all.
ようやく生きてきたかーって感じで、もうマリン以外ありえないですよ。海賊じゃなくて泥棒はね。
It's like, you've finally come to life! It couldn't be anyone but Marine. Not a pirate, but a thief.
もうマリンがありえないです。全部セリフとか振り付けとかも、そういうアハン系でも作ったから。
Marine was just perfect. I made all the lines and choreography in that "Ahan" style.
そうなの。ちょっとマリ箱みたいな動きとかも入ってたりしてね。
That's right. It even had some moves like in "Maribako".
その要素も気づいた？やっぱり。
You noticed those elements? As expected.
当たり前じゃないですか、もう100万回やった光景みたいな感じで。
Of course I did! It felt like a scene I've done a million times.
そうよね。
Right.
いやー、本当に楽しかった。ありがとうね。
Man, it was really fun. Thank you.
あ、そうだ。タルタルお誕生日、おめでとう！
Oh, that's right. Tartar, Happy Birthday!
ありがとうね。
Thank you.
ついでみたいになっちゃったけど、おめでとう！また呼んでくださいね。
It sounded like an afterthought, but congratulations! Please invite me again.
またやろうね。バイバイ。
Let's do it again. Bye-bye.
それでは、今回語り部をやってくれたポルポル！
And now, Pol-pol, who was our narrator!
Omaru Polka
はーい！どうも！
Heeey! Hello!
尾丸ポルカでーす！
I'm Omaru Polka!
大成功です！ポルポル！ありがとうポルポル！
It's a huge success! Pol-pol! Thank you, Pol-pol!
あのさ、もうなんか、わかんない、なんか今回すごいなんか、また新しいの持ってきたね、アキロゼくん。
You know, I don't know how to put it, but you really brought something new again this time, Aki-rose-kun.
そうなんですよ。新しいの持ってきちゃいました、ポルカ先生。
That's right. I brought something new, Polka-sensei.
いやね、ポルカは正直、この立ち位置めちゃくちゃ美味しいもの頂けて、ありがとうございました。
Well, honestly, I got to have such a great role in this position, so thank you very much.
語り部ありがとうございました。
Thank you for the narration.
いやもうね、ポルポルは朗読も好きで結構やってるのも見てたし、合うんよね。
Well, you see, I've seen Pol-pol do readings because she likes them, and it really fits her.
もう、合うんです。
It just fits.
自分でも思うけど、自分で言うのも何なんだけど、私しかできないなと思いながら鼻高々と。
I thought so too, and it might sound a bit much coming from me, but I was thinking "only I could do this" with my head held high.
いや、ポルポルにしかできませんでした。ありがとう。
Indeed, only Pol-pol could have done it. Thank you.
へへ。
Hehe.
いやもう、本当に頭から、中間のね、あらすじみたいなの語ってくれるところから、最後も歌で実は盛り上げてくれるっていうところもありまして。
Yeah, from the very beginning, from the part where you narrated the synopsis-like middle part, to the end where you actually livened things up with a song.
そうなんですよ。なんかさ、語り部なのにこんなにずっと楽しい...まあでも何だろう、ちょっとみんなを引きながら見たりとかして、本当に役的にもすごい美味しかったな。
That's right. Even though I was a narrator, it was so much fun the whole time... Well, I don't know, watching while leading everyone a bit, it was a really great role.
いいよ、本当に。
It's good, really.
好きなの、マジでマリンのところ。というか大泥棒さんのところですね。
I really love Marine's part. Or rather, the great thief's part.
わかる。音変わってさ、来るのがマジで見ていると「うわぁっ」てなる。
I know. When the sound changes and she comes in, it's like "whoa!" when you're watching.
テンションあがっちゃうよね。やっぱり。
It really pumps you up, doesn't it?
いや、そう。多分みんなもそう思ってると思うから、めちゃくちゃ...あそこでガラッと変わって大泥棒のターンになるっていう感じがすごく好き。
Yeah, exactly. I think everyone else feels the same way too, so it's just... I really love how it completely changes there and becomes the thief's turn.
美味しいんですね。ありがとうございます。
It's a great part. Thank you.
推しシーン。はい、ありがとうございます。まあ全体もちろん最高です。こちらからもう以上ですって感じなんだけど。
A favorite scene. Yes, thank you. Well, of course the whole thing was the best. That's all from my side.
ちなみにアキロゼの推しポイントはですね、いっぱいあるんですけど。今回アキロゼの生誕祭なんだけど、まず...
By the way, Aki-rose's favorite points, there are many of them. This is Aki-rose's birthday festival, but first...
…くると言うね。
...coming, right?
そう。
Yeah.
お誕生日でしょ？
It's your birthday, right?
うん。
Yeah.
お誕生日おめでとう、アキロゼ！
Happy birthday, AkiRose!
「え、ポルカ！？」みたいな。
Like, "Wait, Polka!?"
それがまたびっくりで、面白かったんじゃないかなって思ってる。
I think that surprise was really funny.
それはみんな… そう、そうだよね。ごめんね。そうだよね。
Everyone... yeah, that's right. Sorry. You're right.
素敵なプレゼント、ありがとうございました！
Thank you for the wonderful present!
いや、こちらこそおめでとうございます！
No, congratulations to you too!
ありがとうね、ポルポル！
Thank you, Pol-Pol!
みんな、ありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
アキロゼ、おめでとう！
AkiRose, congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
バイバイ！バイバイ！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
Fantasia of Bremen
アキロゼ生誕祭2024
AkiRose Birthday Celebration 2024
【キャスト】
アキ・ローゼンタール / 戌神ころね / 猫又おかゆ
小鳥遊キアラ / 宝鐘マリン / 尾丸ポルカ
[Cast]
Aki Rosenthal / Inugami Korone / Nekomata Okayu
Takanashi Kiara / Houshou Marine / Omaru Polka
【友情出演】
大神ミオ / 白銀ノエル / 常闇トワ / 雪花ラミィ
火威青 / 儒烏風亭らでん / MOTHER3
[Guest Appearances]
Ookami Mio / Shirogane Noel / Tokoyami Towa / Yukihana Lamy
Hiodoshi Ao / Juufuutei Raden / MOTHER3
【使用楽曲】
Welcome to Bremen Music Festival!! / MYSTERIOUS
ドラマツルギー / 秒針を噛む / ミカヅキ
[Music Used]
Welcome to Bremen Music Festival!! / MYSTERIOUS
Dramaturgy / Byoushin wo Kamu / Mikazuki
【コーラス】 アキ・ローゼンタール
【振付】 ミュキュニジマ
[Chorus] Aki Rosenthal
[Choreography] Myu-kunijima
【サムネイルイラスト制作】 塩たこ焼き
【ロゴ制作】 ミナトデザイン
[Thumbnail Illustration] Shiotakoyaki
[Logo Design] Minato Design
【音楽制作】 Symny / E.L.M / クックルP / まつこ
日南めい / 犬絵 / マッチ / KosK
[Music Production] Symny / E.L.M / KukkuruP / Matsuko
Hinami Mei / Inue / Match / KosK
【背景映像制作】 オニマル / Kazu / 紺屋本綴
鈴田的 / hotori / 白水
[Background Visuals] Onimaru / Kazu / Konyahon-tsuzuri
Suzuta Mato / hotori / Shiramizu
【OP映像制作】 鈴田的 / Syamo.G-しゃもじ-
【OP楽曲制作】 ササキ
[OP Movie] Suzuta Mato / Syamo.G-Shamoji-
[OP Song] Sasaki
【ED映像制作】 オムカ / kanmi
[ED Movie] Omuka / kanmi
【企画／構成／総合演出】
アキ・ローゼンタール
[Planning/Composition/General Direction]
Aki Rosenthal
【Special Thanks】
ロゼ隊 / ALL STAFF and You
[Special Thanks]
Rose-tai / ALL STAFF and You